#哈喽大家好
Hi everyone!
#我们这个地方过年的这个气氛还是不错的
The atmosphere of the Chinese New Year here at our place is really good.
#有很多粉丝想看一下我们这个农村坝坝宴是什么样子的
Many fans want to see how the "Ba Ba Yan" ("yard banquet") looks like in our village.
#今天我就带大家去看一下
Let me show you today,
#让在城里的一些没见过的朋友来了解一下我们乡村文化
and let those in the cities know more about our rural culture.
#这个是我们炸好的鱼
These are deep fried fish.
#这一边是青菜（花菜）焯好水的
And the vegetables here have already been blanched.
#这个的话是泥鳅烧的耙泥鳅
And what you see here is "ba niqiu" (Note: Niqiu = loach)
#然后这个是现搭的一个炉灶
And then here is a temporary stove.
#你看下面全是用砖搭起来的围起来的中间烧的是炭火
Have a look at the brick-built base surrounding the fire in the middle.
#里面蒸的是扣肉还有粑粑肉还有一些蒸菜有排骨酥肉这些
Inside the stove are steamed pork belly, ribs and some other stuff.
#我们这个位置是专门摆放凉菜的地方
This place is reserved for cold dishes (appetizer).
#这些虾呀凉菜呀还有一些甜品呀就是饭前甜品全部摆在这个地方 (註︰留意這裡的甜品不能用Dessert，因為Dessert其實是指最後一道菜)
The shrimps, cold dishes and the sweet dishes, I mean the sweet dishes served before the meal, are all placed here.
#这个是我们邻居家的妈妈满80岁过寿宴
This is the 80th birthday banquet of our neighbour's mother.
#所以我们这里摆了坝坝宴
That's why we have a "Ba Ba Yan" here.
#你看人山人海的这上面有7-8桌
Look! There are so many people. There are like 8 tables here.
#摆了7-8桌这上面
About 8 tables here.
#下面我们家的坝子里面摆了10多桌
There are another dozen of tables down there in our yard.
#过年了大家都回来聚在一起
It will soon be the Chinese New Year so everybody is back.
#这个气氛非常的融洽
It's full of harmony.
#也只有过年的时候才能有这种机会
It's not quite possible if it's not the Chinese New Year.
#我觉得也特别不容易
This is really a precious moment, I think.